KUTALMIŞ BERKE YILMAZ

E-mail: kberkeyilmaz@gmail.com || Mobile: +905448169364 || GitHub || Personal App || LinkedIn

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

As a **software developer** with a Bachelor's degree in Translation and Interpretation (French), I bring a strong technical proficiency in JavaScript (**React, jQuery, Next.Js**), CSS (**TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, SASS**), HTML5 and also in backend languages such as **PHP** and **Node.Js**. My experiences span across developing scalable web applications using component libraries such as Material UI, Daisy UI and FramerMotion, Anime.JS etc. With a strong background in translation and CPU technical support, I bring a unique perspective and diverse skillset to

SKILLS

Technical: React.Js, Next.Js, Node.Js, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, SASS, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, HTML5, PHP, SQL.

Languages: English (fluent), French (fluent), Turkish (native).

EXPERIENCE

- Frontend Web Developer, FioresGlobal (Remote) March 2023 July 2023
- Reengineered company's website to improve **accessibility, responsiveness** and **user experience**.
- Enhanced the organization's technical understanding by providing comprehensive insights about **APIs**, backend and frontend responsibilities and **UI/UX** principles.
- MySQL Server Administrator, Frontend Web Developer Mobilpark Communication Softwares (Hybrid) —
 September 2022- March 2023
- Offered consistent customer support and handled client trainings.
- Reinvented the **dashboard design**, emphasizing brand visibility and implemented customer feedback to improve application **UI**.
- Facilitated an increase in operational efficiency.
- Gained exposure to MVC fundamentals.
- Interpreter Ithaki Publishing 2020-2022
- Translations in Sci-fi genre.
- Content proofreading.
- Books to be published: Shrinking Man by Richard Matheson, Devolution by Max Brooks.
- CPU+ Senior Technical Expert, Project Leia, Webhelp Turkey 2018-2020
- Maintained 93% customer satisfaction score with 72% issue resolution over two years.
- Provided mentorship to entry level advisors, reported diverse hardware and software issues to engineering teams.
- Established a gourmet club with over **90 members** and spearheaded various food-oriented events.

EDUCATION

- Interpretation and Translation in French, Marmara University, Istanbul 2016
- Lycée Saint Joseph d'Izmir 2011

Certificates

- Intro to Computer Science Certificate of Success, Izmir Economy University -2022
- DUOLINGO (IELTS EQUIVALENT), Overall Score: 140 (IELTS: C1) 2023
- DELPH, Overall Score: B2 2017
- IELTS Academic, Overall Score: 7,5 2016